GESER DUGAROV, Ph.D.

email: geserdugarov@gmail.com

mobile: +7-913-703-1014

languages: English (advanced), Russian (native)

location: Novosibirsk, Russia

SUMMARY

Made transition to data-driven R&D in the IT industry after 12 yrs in fundamental research. Holds a degree of a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Geophysics. Author and coauthor of more than 50 publications. Experienced in project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Docker, Git, Linux, Matlab

WORK EXPERIENCE

ML Research Engineer, Digital Research (spinoff of Digital Clouds)

II/2022 – current

• Vehicles monitoring (based on computer vision) in the construction industry. Team leader role.

Senior Researcher,

<u>Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics</u>

X/2009 – current

- Experience of technology transfer from fundamental research to business. Team leader role.
- 5 years in a row of personal projects supporting by main foundations (2017-2021).
- 4 graduate students: 3 MSc (2022*2, 2020), 1 BSc (2020).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" award (2019).

Research Associate (II/2014 – IV/2019), Research Assistant (X/2009 – II/2014)

EDUCATION

PhD, Geophysics, X/2009 – XII/2013

Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics SB RAS

(4 years)

MSc, Computational and Applied Mathematics,

IX/2004 - VI/2009

Novosibirsk State University

(5 years)

CERTIFICATES

- Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera (2021).
- Machine Learning, Coursera (2021).

PROJECTS

- XII/2019 VIII/2021 AVAZ inversion of local object anisotropy parameters from 3D seismic data *Role*: **project manager**. *Team size*: 7. Customer: NTC NIS-Naftagas, Serbia.
- VII/2019 VI/2021 Acoustic properties and internal structure of hydrate-bearing coal samples *Role*: **head of the project**. *Team size*: 5. Supported by RSF, grant No. <u>19-77-00068</u>.

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Trofimuk Memorial Medal Award (2021).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" (2019).

HOBBIES

- Going to the gym on a regular basis (since 2019).
- Reading developmental psychology and business management books.

Updated: 29.07.2022, the last version

